Look, ICICI AMC's IPO is not a small IPO.  The
name of the company is also big.
Besides, the IPO issue is also big.  Where the
first issue is being seen for Rs 10,602 crore.
Where I will talk about a good amount of reserve
applications for retail investors only.
Shareholders also remove quotas.
Still it is kept here.  Now the
question is whether we should apply for this IPO
or not?
Because today you have only a few hours
left to apply for this IPO.
Look, the problem is that
people here know that I will almost certainly get the allotment,
but will the GMP be
able to support it or not, the GMP is
looking very small, will there be a negative
listing, will there be a loss if I
take the IPO, so
you will get to see the answer to all these questions in this video,
what does the data actually say,
what does the history say, we will
understand all these things, what subscription are we getting to see within 2 days, we are going to
understand all the data here in this IPO,
so watch the video completely from starting to end, it is going to be a
short video, if
you have not liked the rest of the video yet, then
press the like button.   Let's go
straight to our video.  First of all let us
talk about the anchor book of IPO.
Because anchor book is very
important.  First of all, only
50% of your quota is visible here.
Where we get to see anchors and ex-anchors.
Now
what happens to this anchor investors' money?
50% are logged in for 1 month and the
remaining 50% are logged in for 3 months.   This
means that whatever amount the anchor investors
invest, they already know
that whatever money they invest here will remain
blocked.  So the free float market
cap gets deducted just like that.  Now that
free float market cap will be added when
their logins open.  So
this lock in is kept for the safety of the investors.
So overall let us talk about his anchor book.
So in the anchor book the company has raised
₹322 crore.  Now the company has raised this ₹322 crore
but the good thing is that this
company ICIC AMC is a wealth
management company and all the other wealth
management companies have
invested in this IPO.  Meaning, overall
one thing becomes clear to us that the IPO of
a wealth management
company is coming within an industry.  All other
wealth management companies are investing money there.
Meaning, every company has
full confidence in its industry.  Look, if we
decode the business properly, then this
is such a business where the more the volume
increases, I am not talking only about ICICI AMC.
I am talking about the entire business.
The more the volume increases and
the more money people invest,
the more will be their profit.
What ultimately happens?  Ultimately,
brother, if the AUM of any company where ₹1000 crores has been invested is seen, then
their expense ratio, their
management fee, will
go to them, meaning the more your asset
under management is, the more profit you will make
and I say this every time, friend,
you invest, whatever your profit or loss may be, the
mutual fund houses will take their cut, the
government will take its tax cut and the broker will
take his brokerage, so such companies are
proxy companies of the stock market.
So overall, the
proxy companies of the stock market
benefit and the market
also gives higher valuation to such companies.  Like
we saw NSDL's IPO coming recently.  There
is strong QIB subscription there too.  And one more thing is that
strong subscription of KYB is also
seen in these companies.  Now let us talk about ICICI AMC
only.  Where there is a
zone of KYB, it is quite high in any IPO.
Because if a retail
investor invests money in any IPO,
his thinking is that I will get
listing gain and I will exit.  So
actually if a seller is available then the
buyer against him should also be available.  The
more multiple we
get to see the subscription of KYB, the
more KYBs are interested in buying that stock
and actually those who
decide the listing price, that is, those who
move the stock, are done by the
institutions only.  This means that the company
for which there is more demand from QIBs for the IPO will be
listed at a higher price.
Because those KYBs who did not
get allotment demand any share at a higher price.
This is the basic formula
of IPO.  Meaning, you should understand one thing, there are two things
in QBIS, first there is one anchor,
ex anchor, so if the anchor investor is very
good, it means that the share will do well in a period of 1 to 3 months,
if the QB subscription is very good, it
means you will get good listing end, keep these two
things and two formulas in your mind,
if you invest in IPO, then
what does this data say,
when does the QB subscription come, generally it
comes around 2-3 pm on day three, because if
QBIS keeps its money blocked for two extra days, then
extra
interest will be charged on it, there is an opportunity cost for
investing such a huge amount of money.
Ok?  So, in a company which is
getting good KYB subscription on the first or second day, there is a
high probability that
strong KYB subscription will be seen coming on the third day also.
Now on the first day,
this IPO gets an oversubscription of 1.97x.
Now, if a small IPO gets 2X more
subscription, we would say that since the
size of the IPO is small, the investment will be
less if there is multifold subscription.
But here the IPO is big.  This
is an IPO of Rs 10,602 crore.  So here
you have two times more subscription on the first day.
Meaning, we understood a picture that brother
also has a strong interest in it.  Let's talk about the next day.  Let's
talk about day two.
So they have already reached Day 2.  It
almost became 2.91x.
Which IPOs offer 3x subscription at the end of Day 2
?  Please tell me this.  You must have
checked many IPOs.  I can't find it
brother.  It is not available generally.  Ok?  This means that
we are getting clarity that on the
third day we will see an explosion somewhere.  I
mean, I am not saying that it will definitely happen
but we
can have some hope.  You may be optimistic that your
brother will definitely come somewhere on the third day.
And I am not saying that
if I feel like this then I will
apply in advance.  No, let's keep the KYB
subscription coming.  Let's find out what the picture is.
After that I apply.
Now let's talk about our chances of allotment.
Look
what was there for retail investors?  27 lakh
applications were kept reserved.
Obviously your quota becomes 33.25.
Something has come out from there for the shareholder quota.
So let us first understand the shareholder quota.
So, approximately 4 lakh applications were reserved in your shareholder quota.
Clearly doesn't show you any numbers here.
But we will divide the number of shares kept reserved
by the shares of one lot.  So
we get to see these 4 lakh lots.
So this much reservation is there.  Ok?  Well, if
I talk about shares, 24.48
lakh of your reserve shares were
kept in the shareholder quota.  Where
how much has already come at this time?  Approximately 69 lakh of your
applications are pending.  I'm going to go into the thicker side of us clearly about 3x here.
So three times the
shareholder quota here has been subscribed.
What's the worst that can happen?  It will last up
to 10 times.  So if you
try to hit up to 10 lots from one account,
you will get confirmed allotment here.
Besides, in retail only one lot
works.  So how much has happened at this time
?  Almost yours is done ah close to 13 lakh to be
precise 13.89
lakh.  13,9000 applications are received within 2 days.
See what happens generally?  Application is required
as per the subscription increase in 2 days.
Almost the same amount falls on the third day.
I accept that
brother, it has happened now, it will go above 15
, it will go above 17.  The total number of
applications worth Rs 30 lakh will be 1920.  30 lakhs should be gone.
Still, if 30 lakh applications come,
32 lakh also come, 35 lakh also come.
Still, 27 out of 30 will get allotment.
Meaning the probability of our allotment
is high.  So everything
seems positive.  Some time
ago, the IPO of HDB Financials came.   There were some
great things to see there too.  There was a
similar scene.  A good number of people made a
profit of Rs 2000-2500.  So that's a
good thing.  Ok?  Rest I will talk about
Big HI category where we apply for Rs 10 lakh.
Your
48 thousand applications were kept reserved here.
Where 36,000 applications have been received
and generally the big amount required is
paid on the last day only.  So here we are seeing 0.74x
application wise over subscription right now
but we will
also see it increasing.  If I talk about the rest of the small HAI category, then
your 24 lakh sorry 24000
applications have been kept reserved here,
83,000 have already been received here and
this is the worst category brother.
3.5x has already arrived here.  This is a big IPO.
Otherwise, if there was a small IPO of such a branded
company, then some brothers would not have been able to handle the small HAI quota.
So overall you do
n't need to say much.  The conclusion will be in
front of you.  Because look, I am
not saying that there will definitely be profit here.
But when you do not get allotment, when
such an IPO is coming after years where there are
some chances of profit and you will get
allotment, then do it in such a situation
brother.  What's the problem?  Right now, to
take a loss on such an IPO would mean taking a bullet to the chest.
This is what I mean to say.  Ok
?  So if you get something then it
becomes your duty to grab it.  I am speaking my mind.
I will apply with full four.
Whatever else is yours, you make your own decision brother.
I am not imposing any decision on you.
I am not an investment advisor.  If you make a
profit, even if you incur a loss,
you have no problem.  If you like the video
then like it.  I will give you all the remaining updates on the
KYB subscription which will come around 3:00 pm
on the telegram channel.   There
is a link to the Telegram channel in the description.  Go and join quickly.  I'll see
you in the next new video.  If you
want such reviews, analysis
related to IPO and market, then subscribe.
See you in the next new video.  Bye Bye
Tata Jai ​​Hind Jai